Contact

Phone

+91 9946585714 +91 7907575946

Email

devusm@gmail.com

Address

22/1524 A, Pily Lane Mundamveli P O Kochi, Ernakulam, Kerala, India

https://www.linkedin.com/in/devu-s-murali-b1516315b

https://www.facebook.com/devu.murali

Education

2008 - 2013

B.Tech In Computer Science and Engineering (Equivalent to a bachelor's degree as determined by World Education Services in Toronto, ON) RIT, Kottayam, Kerala, India

2005 - 2007

Plus Two

GGHSS, Cherthala, Kerala, India

2005

SSLC

MTHS, Alappuzha, Kerala, India

Websites Created

https://www.paci.ai/

htttp://cctecsoftware.com/

https://www.sherrypapers.com/

http://skylinesigners.com/

https://www.bellevuevillage.ca/

https://pedrr.org/MOOC/

https://www.merchsupersystem.com/

https://www.centre-a.com/

https://electronikmedia.com/development/cosmere/

https://www.morrislegalgroup.com.au/

Devu Sudha Murali

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Profile

As a 10-year experienced front-end developer, I have a strong understanding of web development principles and experience in creating beautiful and user-friendly web applications.

Throughout my career, I have been recognized for my ability to collaborate effectively with designers and other developers to deliver high-quality products on time and within budget. I have experience working in agile environments and am familiar with tools such as Jira and Git.In addition to my technical skills, I am a strong communicator and problem solver. I enjoy staying up-to-date on the latest trends and best practices in front-end development and regularly attend industry conferences and meetups to continue learning.

Experience

Front End Developer (NOC: 21234)

Electronikmedia, Kochi, Kerala, India

01/2021 - Present

- Responsible for developing the front end of a learning app using react native, AWS amplify and firebase
- Followed SDLC best practices within Agile environment like Jira to produce rapid iterations for clients.
- Daily maintenance of code, debugging issues and solving client's problems. Presented findings in a clear and concise way of scrum calls.
- Collaborated with back-end developers to determine solutions that easily integrate with new and/or existing APIs into the front end of a website.
- Solid experience with version control tools, preferably git.

Front End Developer (NOC: 21234)

Vividreal Solutions Pvt Ltd, Kochi, Kerala, India 06/2020 - 01/2021

- Coordinated with digital content manager to obtain content for updates and expansions.
- Liaised between marketing and IT on web development projects integrating front-end assets to back-end systems.
- Experience in teaching and guiding other developers on subjects where they need mentoring.
- Familiarity with RESTful APIs, Strong problem-solving and analytical skills
- Ensured code is well written and follows company patterns, standards and practices.

Front End Developer (NOC: 21234)

Novo Software Solutions, Kochi , Kerala, India 04/2013 - 03/2020

- Implemented websites, mobile applications, and landing pages from concept through deployment. Ensured end-to-end process of data extraction until reporting.
- Standardized all output with a new, responsive, mobile-first approach and strategy. Assessed UX and UI designs for technical feasibility.
- Implemented complex website designs based on client approved mockups with advanced front-end coding using a combination of HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Javascript/jQuery that will deliver an optimized user experience using WordPress and front-end frameworks like Bootstrap, Foundation.

Tech Stack

Javascript	•	•	•	•
React Native	•	•	•	•
JQuery	•	•	•	•
HTML5	•	•	•	•
CSS3	•	•	•	•
Responsive	•	•	•	•
Jira	•	•	•	•
Bootstrap	•	•	•	•
Photoshop	•	•	•	•
Illustrator	•	•	•	•
Wordpress	•	•	•	•
SASS	•	•	•	•
Git	•	•	•	•
Basecamp	•	•	•	•

Projects

RISE

- Built a web-based data-driven tool with a survey feature for data collection from various entities including clients, associations, partners and vendors. Based on the collected information, display various reporting dashboards for its users to understand the financial spending of their organizations and compare it with the industry average and local census data. Thereby helping them to optimize and improve the hiring and purchasing process to be in line with the organization goals
- Worked on the front end part using angular 12 and typescript.
- Collaborated with back-end developers to determine solutions that easily integrate with new API into the front-end of the application.
- Ensure projects are delivered on time and within budget using Agile methodologies, mainly Jira.
- Participated in all team activities and agile processes: scrum, refining, retrospective, etc.

Tackl

- Built a learning mobile app for medical students with question bank, Quiz,
 Test series using react native.
- Worked on the front end part using react native.
- Created social media authentication using AWS amplify, firebase.
- Ensure projects are delivered on time and within budget using Agile methodologies, mainly Jira.
- Participated in all team activities and agile processes: scrum, refining, retrospective, etc.
- Solid experience with version control tools, preferably git.
 we used BitBucket.
- Ensure solutions are released properly and the release is documented.

QE Project

- To build a software web app to manage the projects in the quality assurance team with react in front end and .Net in backend system.
- I contributed in the jira integration part into the front end using react.
- Get the details of the whole projects in jira like the status of the issues,
 Comments from QA and developers, etc.
- Created a dashboard for displaying progress of the projects in QA and show the report using chart, graph

HRMS

- To build a Human Resource Management Software web app using Angular as the frontend and node js as the backend.
- I contributed mainly on the frontend angular part, focused on building reusable components and building routes for the system.
- Collaborated with back-end developers to determine solutions that easily integrate with new and/or existing API into the front-end.
- Used reactive forms for handling large forms.